A Guide to the Vincent P. Dole papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, Correspondence, Series 1 FA730
Rockefeller Archive Center
Vincent P. Dole papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, Correspondence, Series 1
1941-1995
Rockefeller Archive Center
Dole, Vincent
FA730
21.2 Cubic Feet
48 document boxes.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 450 D688
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Biographical / Historical
Vincent P. Dole (1913-2006) was an American physician, clinician, and professor emeritus of Rockefeller University best known for developing methadone maintenance treatment for heroin addiction with his wife, psychiatrist Marie Nyswander (1919-1986). Born in Chicago in 1913, Dole obtained his undergraduate degree in mathematics from Stanford University in 1934 before studying medicine at Harvard University, receiving his M.D. in 1939. He joined the Rockefeller Institute (which later became the Rockefeller University) in 1941, where his early research focused on the role that sodium and lipids played in metabolism, obesity, and high blood pressure. His work during this time, including a liquid diet that he developed, received professional and commercial attention.
In the early 1960’s, Dr. Dole became troubled by the growing drug problem in New York City and decided to devote his laboratory to the study of addiction from a metabolic perspective. He consulted Dr. Marie Nyswander, the only person working in the field at the time who considered drug addiction to be a disease and not a personality defect. During their research in 1964 and 1965, they noticed a significant difference in the ways patients responded to methadone compared to the other substances they were testing. Methadone, a synthetic opioid developed in Germany during World War II, blocked patients’ insatiable craving for heroin and restored their self-worth and ability to lead productive lives, as opposed to the extremely low retention rates and high relapse rates of programs that abruptly detoxed patients or attempted to eliminate their socially destructive tendencies, which Dole and Nyswander interpreted as drug-seeking behavior fueled by a disease kept in check by regular doses of methadone, comparable to a diabetic’s need for insulin.
Dole and Nyswander received widespread recognition for their work in scientific communities and addiction communities alike. They were the recipients of the first annual Nyswander-Dole award in 1982, sponsored by the New York Urban Coalition, the New York State Division of Substance Abuse, and the Committee of Methadone Program Administrations. Dole also was the recipient of the prestigious Lasker Prize in 1988 and the Prince Mahidol Award in 1996. He was the author of over 100 scientific papers. Dr. Dole was also involved in national and local drug policy throughout his career, and maintained connections with legislators, bureaucrats, and other influential figures in addiction administration and local, state, and national government. He was involved in a consulting capacity with many methadone maintenance treatment programs in hospitals, prisons, local and state governments, and independent facilities. Later in his career, Dole shifted the focus of his research to alcoholism. At the time of his retirement in the 1990’s, he was attempting to determine alcoholic tendencies in mice. He served on the board of trustees of Alcoholics Anonymous and was an elected member and later a fellow of the National Academy of Sciences and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. At the time of his death in 2006, there were over 1 million methadone treated patients world-wide.
Arrangement
Series 1: Correspondence
Conditions Governing Access
This series is open for scholarly research.
Material containing sensitive information and correspondence with living members of the Rockefeller family is restricted. In most cases, restricted material will be open 50 years after creation.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Separated Materials
Special Formats (audio, film, video, digital media, library materials, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the body of the collection to facilitate stabilization, migration, and long-term preservation. All pertinent items are assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Dole, Vincent
- Correspondence, 1960-1995; 1; 21.2 Box(es)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the professional correspondence of Dr. Vincent P. Dole. Much of the content deals with his work in lipid chemistry and addiction pharmacology, especially his development of methadone maintenance in the 1960’s and continued involvement with addiction medicine and drug policy. Many of the correspondents are his colleagues at the Rockefeller University, Beth Israel Medical Center, bureaucrats and legislators involved in drug policy, and other scientists and doctors interested in methadone from across the United States and the world.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent, subject, institution, or occasionally the geographical location of the subject or correspondent. Each folder is arranged in reverse chronological order. In miscellaneous folders that contain more than one correspondent, the items within the folders are arranged alphabetically by correspondent and then reverse chronologically.
  - A Misc, 1966-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Misc (Box 1, Folder 1A)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Closed to scholarly research. The material will be opened 50 years after the date of creation.
  - Academic Press, Inc, 1979-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Addiction Research Center, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Addiction Research Foundation, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adolescent Clinics, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Advances in Alcohol & Substance Abuse, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alcoholism and Drug Abuse Institute, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alexander, Bruce K., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Allfrey, Vincent G., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Analytical Biochemistry, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - B Misc (1 of 2), 1966-1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - B Misc (2 of 2), 1967-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - B Misc (Box 1, Folder 12A)
    Material containing sensitive information has been separated and placed into a closed folder. The material will be opened 50 years after the date of creation.
  - Bahna, Geraldine, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Balboni, Victor G., 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ball, John C. (1 of 2), 1966-1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ball, John C. (2 of 2), 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Baltimore, David, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Barnell, Jim, 1977-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Barnell, Jim (Box 2, Folder 18A)
  - Batey, R., 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bayer, Ronald, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bearn, Alexander G., 1972-1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bechgaard, Poul, 1975-1995 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Becker, William H., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Berger, Herbert, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Berle, Beatrice B., 1963-1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Berridge, Virginia, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Beth Israel Medical Center "Brain Trust", 1986 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Biemiller, Reynard, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Bihari, Bernard (1 of 2), 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Bihari, Bernard (2 of 2), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bihari, Bernard (Box 3, Folder 30A)
  - Black Man's Development Center (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Blankenhorn, David, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Blansfield, Henry N., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Blomstrand, Rolf, 1976-1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Blum, Kenneth, 1979-1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Blumberg, Irving, 1968-1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bogdanovic, Sinisa B., 1975-1993 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bourne, Peter G., 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Brecher, Edward M., 1967-1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Brill, Henry, 1966-1976 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Brill, Leon, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Brooklyn Comprehensive Corporation, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Brown, Barry S., 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Brown, Claude, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Bryant, Thomas E., 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Bucaro, Andrew G., 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Burden, Carter, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Byrne, Andrew, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - C Misc (1 of 2), 1967-1993 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - C Misc (2 of 2), 1966-1993 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - C Misc (Box 4, Folder 50A)
  - California M.M.T.P, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - California M.M.T.P. (Box 5, Folder 51A)
  - California Society for the Treatment of Alcoholism and Other Drug Dependencies, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Caplehorn, John, 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Cerami, Anthony, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Chalmers, Thomas C., 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Chance, Britton, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Chase, Gordon, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Chemical & Engineering News, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Clouet, Doris H., 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Condelli, Ward S., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Connecticut M.M.T.P., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Cooper, James R., 1994 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Copyright Permission, 1984-1993 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Cotzias, George C. (Biography) (1 of 2), 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    Correspondence relating to a biography of Cotzias that Dole wrote for the National Academy of Sciences
  - Cotzias, George C. (Biography) (2 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Cotzias, George C. (Personal Correspondence), 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    Personal and professional correspondence between Cotzias and Dole
  - Cotzias, George C. (Personal Correspondence) (Box 5, Folder 66A)
  - Cournand, Andé, 1975-1991 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Court Cases, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Cranefield, Paul F., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    Correspondence relating to the promotion of Dr. Cranefield at Rockefeller University
  - Crawford, Bryce, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Creech, Philip H. (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - CSR Inc., 1992 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Curtis, James L., 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Cushman, Paul, 1969-1989 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Tape of Methadone Program, ca. 1973; 2001:025:001; Cassette
      RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
      Separated Materials
      The items has been separated from the body of the collection to facilitate stabilization, migration, and long-term preservation. All pertinent items are assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - Cushman, Paul (Box 6, Folder 74A)
  - Czechowicz, Dorynne, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - D Misc, 1967-1985 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - D Misc (Box 6, Folder 76A)
  - Dahl, Lewis K., 1987 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Dahlem Conference, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Darling Foundation, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Davis, Bernard, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Deglon, Jean-Jacques, 1984-1992 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Delaware M.M.T.P., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Denton, Derek, 1982-1996 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Des Jarlais, Don C., 1977-1995 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Detoxification, 1971-1976 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Detoxification (Box 8, Folder 85A)
  - Deuschle, Kurt W., 1972-1977 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Diet (Liquid Formula), 1955-1977 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Dilworth, J. Richardson, 1967-1979 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Documentation Associates, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Dress, Barry W., 1983-1987 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Drew, Alan, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Drucker, Ernest, 1985-1996 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Drug Abuse Council, 1971-1977 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Drug and Alcohol Dependence, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Drug Dependence Associates, Inc., 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Drug Laws, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Dubin, Gerald, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Dubos, Jean and René, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Düchting, Werner, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - DuPont, Robert L. (1 of 3), 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - DuPont, Robert L. (2 of 3), 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - DuPont, Robert L. (3 of 3), 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - E Misc, 1966-1993 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - E Misc (Box 10, Folder 103A)
  - Eddy, Nathan B., 1963-1973 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Eddy, Nathan B. (Box 10, Folder 104A)
  - Edelman, Gerald M., 1982-1991 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Education of Physician-Scholars for Leadership in the Health Care System, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Edwards, Don, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Edwards, Griffith, 1970-1992 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Einstein, Stanley, 1971-1986 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Emerson, Lee, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 110)
    Various clippings about Dr. Lee
  - Enciso, William, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Endo Laboratories, Inc., 1969-1977 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - European Methadone Association, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - External Advisory Board NIDA/VA, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - F Misc, 1969-1991 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - F Misc (Box 10, Folder 115A)
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Feldberg, Stephen, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Fishman, Jack (1 of 2), 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Fishman, Jack (2 of 2), 1976-1979 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - FitzGerald, William A., 1974-1985 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Flexner Colloquium, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Foley, Kathleen, 1977-1984 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Foley, Kathleen (Box 12, Folder 122A)
  - Food and Drug Administration, 1982-1987 (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Fredrickson, Donald S., 1975-1991 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - G Misc (1 of 3), 1967-1985 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - G Misc (2 of 3), 1969-1992 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - G Misc (3 of 3), 1966-1992 (Box 12, Folder 127)
  - G Misc (Box 12, Folder 127A)
  - Garrett, Franklin, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 128)
  - Gaston, Arnett W., 1976 (Box 12, Folder 129)
  - Gearing, Frances R. (1 of 2), 1972-1979 (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Gearing, Frances R. (2 of 2), 1965-1971 (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - Genest, Jacques, 1968-1996 (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - Gentry, R. Thomas (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - Gentry, R. Thomas (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Gessa, Gian Luigi, 1981-1994 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Glaser, Frederick B., 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Glass, Richard M., 1992-1995 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Glieman, Jørgen, 1969-1977 (Box 14, Folder 138)
  - Golden, William T., 1994 (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - Goldhaber, Maurice, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - Goldin, Harrison J., 1973 (Box 14, Folder 141)
  - Goldstein, Avram (1 of 2), 1970-1996 (Box 14, Folder 142)
  - Goldstein, Avram (2 of 2), 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 143)
  - Goldstein, Avram (Box 14, Folder 143A)
  - Goldstein, Dora, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Goldstine, Herman, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 145)
  - Gollance, Harvey, 1969-1977 (Box 14, Folder 146)
  - Goodman, Aubrey L., 1965-1972 (Box 15, Folder 147)
  - Goodman, Aubrey L. (Box 15, Folder 147A)
  - Gordis, Enoch (1 of 4), 1989-1996 (Box 15, Folder 148)
  - Gordis, Enoch (2 of 4), 1986-1989 (Box 15, Folder 149)
  - Gordis, Enoch (3 of 4), 1979-1984 (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Gordis, Enoch (4 of 4), 1967-1976 (Box 15, Folder 151)
  - Gordon, Edward, 1968-1974 (Box 15, Folder 152)
  - Gordon, Norman B. (1 of 2), 1971-1978 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - Gordon, Norman B. (2 of 2), 1966-1971 (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - Gordon Research Conferences, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - Green, Jack Peter, 1967-1990 (Box 16, Folder 156)
  - Greengaard, Paul, 1989-1991 (Box 16, Folder 157)
  - Greenwich House Counseling Center, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 158)
  - Greenwich House Counseling Center (Box 16, Folder 158A)
  - Griffin, Donald R., 1978-1995 (Box 16, Folder 159)
  - Gunne, Lars-M., 1969-1995 (Box 16, Folder 160)
  - H Misc (1 of 2), 1968-1994 (Box 16, Folder 161)
  - H Misc (2 of 2), 1967-1989 (Box 17, Folder 162)
  - H Misc (Box 17, Folder 162A)
  - Halikas, James A., 1991 (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - Hallin, Susan, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - Hartel, Diana (1 of 2), 1990-1993 (Box 17, Folder 165)
  - Hartel, Diana (2 of 2), 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - Harvard, 1976-1994 (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Harvey, A. McGehee, 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 168)
  - Hawaii M.M.T.P., 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 169)
  - Haworth Press, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Heaston, Donald D. (Box 18, Folder 171)
  - Helpern, Milton, 1973-1977 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - Helpern, Milton (Box 18, Folder 172A)
  - Hertz Corporation, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - Hess Thaysen Jørn, 1966-1996 (Box 18, Folder 174)
  - Hewlett Packard, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Hirsch, Jules, 1970-1995 (Box 18, Folder 176)
  - Hoffman, Jeffrey A., 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 177)
  - Hoffman-La Roche and Company, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 178)
  - Hollenberg, Harvard, 1976-1978 (Box 18, Folder 179)
  - Holmstedt, Bo, 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 180)
  - Holmstedt, Bo (Box 18, Folder 180A)
  - Hovakimian, Aram, 1975-1981 (Box 18, Folder 181)
  - Howlett, Robert, 1974-1989 (Box 18, Folder 182)
  - Hughes, Harold E., 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 183)
  - Hunt, Walter A., 1993 (Box 18, Folder 184)
  - Hutt, Peter Barton, 1969-1979 (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - Hutt, Peter Barton (Box 18, Folder 185A)
  - I Misc, 1966-1983 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - I Misc (Box 18, Folder 186A)
  - ICN Biochemicals, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Ingoglia, Nicholas A., 1972-1987 (Box 19, Folder 188)
  - Institute for the Study of Drug Addiction, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 189)
  - Interim Clinics, 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 190)
  - Inter-Institutional Workshop, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 191)
  - International Society for Biomedical Research on Alcoholism, 1986-1994 (Box 19, Folder 192)
  - Isbell, Harris, 1966-1975 (Box 19, Folder 193)
  - Itoh, Shinji, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 194)
  - J Misc, 1952-1982 (Box 19, Folder 195)
  - J Misc (Box 19, Folder 195A)
  - Jaffe, Jerome H., 1968-1977 (Box 19, Folder 196)
  - Jail Project Outreach, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 197)
  - James, Anthony T., 1957-1992 (Box 19, Folder 198)
  - Jan, M. Rafiq, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - Jan, M. Rafiq (Box 19, Folder 199A)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1966-1976 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - Jeanrenaud, Bernard, 1966-1979 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - Jepsen, Jørgen, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 202)
  - Jersild, Torben, 1972-1977 (Box 20, Folder 203)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 204)
  - Johnson, Thomas, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 205)
  - Joseph, Herman, 1968-1996 (Box 20, Folder 206)
  - Joseph, Herman (Box 20, Folder 206A)
  - Joseph, Stephen C., 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 207)
  - Journal of the American Medical Association, 1958-1995 (Box 20, Folder 208)
  - Journal of Clinical Investigation, 1952-1964 (Box 20, Folder 209)
  - Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1955-1973 (Box 20, Folder 210)
  - Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, 1963-1965 (Box 20, Folder 211)
  - Journal of Lipid Research, 1959-1964 (Box 20, Folder 212)
  - Journal of Maintenance in the Addictions, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 213)
  - K Misc (1 of 2), 1963-1989 (Box 21, Folder 214)
  - K Misc (2 of 2), 1960-1992 (Box 21, Folder 215)
  - K Misc (Box 21, Folder 215A)
  - Kalant, Harold, 1979-1993 (Box 21, Folder 216)
  - Kaplan, Marc, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 217)
  - Karlin, Arthur, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 218)
  - Keeley, Kim A., 1977 (Box 21, Folder 219)
  - Kell, Michael J. (1 of 2), 1993-1996 (Box 21, Folder 220)
  - Kell, Michael J. (2 of 2), 1993 (Box 21, Folder 221)
    - Million Clinical Multiavial Inventory, undated; 2000:085:001; floppy disk.; floppy disk
      The item has been separated from the body of the collection to facilitate stabilization and long-term preservation. All pertient items are assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
      RAC is unable to provide direct access to original digital media files. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
    - Extended Score Report, undated; 2000:085:001; Floppy disk.; floppy disk
  - Kellogg Foundation (1 of 2), 1982-1999 (Box 22, Folder 222)
  - Kellogg Foundation (2 of 2), 1979-1982 (Box 22, Folder 223)
  - Kent, Bertram, 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 224)
  - Kessler, Richard, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 225)
  - Killip, Thomas, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 226)
  - Kleber, Herbert D., 1989 (Box 22, Folder 227)
  - Klepak, Daniel, 1976-1978 (Box 22, Folder 228)
  - Klieber, Dorothea (Box 22, Folder 229)
  - Koch, Edward I., 1969-1988 (Box 22, Folder 230)
  - Kovin, John F., 1970 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - Kramer, John C., 1968-1976 (Box 22, Folder 232)
  - Kramer, John C. (Box 22, Folder 232A)
  - Krause, Richard M., 1979 (Box 22, Folder 233)
  - Kuhar, Michael J., 1990 (Box 22, Folder 234)
  - L Misc (1 of 2), 1950-1986 (Box 23, Folder 235)
  - L Misc (2 of 2), 1951-1993 (Box 23, Folder 236)
  - L Misc (Box 23, Folder 236A)
  - Ladopoulous, Constantine, P., 1981 (Box 23, Folder 237)
  - Lamberts, Henk, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 238)
  - Langrod, John, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 239)
  - LaPorte, Charles, 1981-1990 (Box 23, Folder 240)
  - LaPorte, Charles (Box 23, Folder 240A)
  - Lasker Foundation, 1969-1996 (Box 23, Folder 241)
  - Lawler, Joseph G. (Box 23, Folder 242)
  - Lee, Peter E.I., 1978-1994 (Box 23, Folder 243)
  - Lee, T.D., 1994 (Box 23, Folder 244)
  - Leichter, Thomas, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 245)
  - Lehrman, Nathaniel S., 1980 (Box 24, Folder 246)
  - Lemes, Andrew J. (Box 24, Folder 247)
  - Leshin, Philip, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 248)
  - Letters of Praise, 1953-1989 (Box 24, Folder 249)
  - Levy, Barry (Box 24, Folder 250)
  - Lewis, David C., 1992 (Box 24, Folder 251)
  - Li, Kelvin (Box 24, Folder 252)
  - Lieber, Charles S., 1986-1994 (Box 24, Folder 253)
  - Lilly Research Laboratories, 1962-1975 (Box 24, Folder 254)
  - Lindesmith, Alfred R., 1965-1976 (Box 24, Folder 255)
  - Lindesmith Center, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 256)
  - Lipton, Douglas S., 1974-1978 (Box 24, Folder 257)
  - Loew, Gilda Harris, 1978-1990 (Box 24, Folder 258)
  - Longsworth, Lewis G., 1978-1981 (Box 24, Folder 259)
  - Louisiana (1 of 2), 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 260)
  - Louisiana (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 261)
  - Louisiana (Box 25, Folder 261A)
  - Loveland, David B., 1976-1985 (Box 25, Folder 262)
  - Lower East Side Service Center, 1984-1989 (Box 25, Folder 263)
  - Luft, Rolf, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 264)
  - Lundstedt, Claus, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 265)
  - M Misc (1 of 2), 1965-1991 (Box 25, Folder 266)
  - M Misc (2 of 2), 1959-1986 (Box 25, Folder 267)
  - M Misc (Box 25, Folder 267A)
  - MacDonald, Angus N., 1969-1974 (Box 26, Folder 268)
  - MacDonald, Ian, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 269)
  - Mac Lane, Saunders, 1977-1991 (Box 26, Folder 270)
  - MacLeod, Colin M., 1964-1965 (Box 26, Folder 271)
  - Macy Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 272)
  - Maier, Jan, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 273)
  - Malcolm, Benjamin J., 1973-1984 (Box 26, Folder 274)
  - Maremmani, Icro, 1993-1995 (Box 26, Folder 275)